Di.
Di!
We confirmed
Zheng Kai has the long saber.
It's refined military steel.
Master.
We found the physical evidence.
Why do you look so grim?
When I was sewing up Madam Shen's body,
the edges were jagged
and showed signs of secondary tearing.
There were gaps along the suture line.
It wasn't the blade
that killed Liu Wang.
We're definitely missing a clue.
=The Tang Mist S1=
=Episode 18=
(If both murders)
(were done by the same person,)
(why switch weapons?)
(But if they weren't,)
(then Madam Shen's killer)
(was just copying the Colossus.)
(To what end?)
(How are the two killers connected?)
(As for Liu Wang,)
(whose cold case did he find?)
(Wu shall die!)
(Why would the Colossus)
(target the Heavenly Empress?)
(What is Luling hiding?)
(The abducted
pregnant women in Yunluo Village.)
In such a short time,
ten expectant mothers were taken.
And one of them
was of the Cui clan of Qinghe.
To think Liu Wang
hoarded a 15-year-old case file.
(Zhao Qin Wanwan)
He even kept the list
(Zhu Li Guiying, Li Sun Nianqing)
of their exact due dates.
Why abduct pregnant women?
I know.
The culprits were never caught.
Liu Wang figured out who they were,
and was silenced.
But pointing the finger at the court?
Wouldn't that just invite trouble?
Well...
If we think outside the box,
and re-evaluate everything.
Liu Wang
(Reporter: Resident of Yunluo Village)
discovered the truth behind
(Consultation for Zheng Cui Lanqing)
the abductions from fifteen years ago.
He took his findings to Madam Shen.
As the Commandant's wife,
she wouldn't have gotten involved
unless there was
something in it for her.
If there were two killers,
it means
the killers shared the same motive.
To bury the truth
of what happened fifteen years ago.
Master,
we have no proof.
Commissioner Di.
Allow me to toast you with tea.
We do.
Duan.
Buyan.
Head to Yunluo Village.
Qinglan,
you're with me.
Sir. I picked up some breakfast.
I hope it's to your liking.
You've been up all night...
Lin.
The long sleep must be exhausting.
Nonsense.
Who slept all night?
I was investigating.
You can't even read.
What were you investigating?
Commissioner Di,
your visit was so sudden.
The meal is quite simple.
I hope you don't mind.
Luling County hasn't
been very peaceful lately.
Last night,
thieves broke into the Garrison.
Commissioner Di,
you should also be very careful.
Oh?
Is that so?
Xu Tong didn't mention it?
How is Xu Tong even an official?
This is a serious incident!
Why didn't he inform me?
Xu Tong has some nerve.
He clearly has no respect for you, sir.
Never mind that.
Catching the culprits
and giving the Garrison an explanation
is what matters.
Otherwise,
I'll make sure he gets
a good flogging.
Someone must be talking about me.
As a commoner,
it is an honor to share a drink
with such prestigious guests.
Allow me to toast you with tea
to express my deepest gratitude.
You're too kind, Young Lady Qinglan.
Drink.
I'm not drinking this.
Qi. Toast Commissioner Di
on your father's behalf.
Here.
Something just came to mind.
What is it?
Yesterday,
I heard something at the Bureau.
Pregnant women were abducted
in Yunluo Village fifteen years ago.
I heard
that you, Madam Cui,
were also taken by the kidnappers.
Mother,
were you hurt?
Why haven't you ever mentioned this?
There's no need to panic.
It's all in the past.
It's not worth mentioning.
This case is connected
to Liu Wang's death.
Madam Cui, please,
tell me what happened
back then.
Well...
Back then,
I was pregnant with Qi.
I was due any day.
But as the day drew closer,
I felt an overwhelming sense of dread.
So,
I went to Zhaoyun Temple
despite being heavily pregnant,
to pray for the child.
But on the way back,
they suddenly...
You dare
block a carriage from the Garrison?
The person in the carriage stays.
Everyone else,
get lost.
In that case,
Young Master Yunqi
is truly blessed.
To survive such a disaster
and walk away completely unscathed.
Not to mention
he's grown up to be handsome,
incredibly virtuous,
and exceptionally talented.
He certainly lives up to
the bloodlines
of the Zheng and Cui clans.
What's wrong with the young master?
What's wrong with my son?
It's hives.
Perhaps he has some kind of allergy.
Qi.
What...
What did you just eat?
Commandant Zheng dislikes jasmine,
but that's understandable.
But Madam Cui, you love jasmine tea.
How is it that for fifteen years,
you never knew
your own son was allergic to it?
The jasmine...
I didn't want to worry Mother,
so I kept it a secret.
It's not her fault.
It's my fault.
I was careless.
Well?
She smells of lovage root, nutgrass,
and several other herbs.
Among them,
the scent of dodder seed
and deer antler is the strongest.
These are highly potent tonics.
A proper physician would
never mix them together.
It's common knowledge
they shouldn't be combined.
But judging by her pulse,
it all makes perfect sense.
What kind of pulse?
Madam.
Let me.
That of a barren woman.
She took any remedies she could find.
Then, it all makes sense.
Every single move
Madam Cui makes
is tightly bound to
her family's reputation.
If word got out that she was barren,
her family would lose face.
Therefore,
she staged a fake pregnancy,
using kidnappers as a cover.
And Zheng Yunqi
is the living proof.
But she already had Zheng Yunqi.
Why would she murder Madam Shen?
Because Zheng Yunqi
has the blood of a commoner.
The child Madam Shen bore, however,
carried the true Zheng bloodline.
And so,
just like she did fifteen years ago,
she killed the mother to steal the child.
So Liu Wang
was also murdered by Madam Cui?
The truth will reveal itself soon enough.
Master!
Di!
Master.
We went to Yunluo Village.
Fifteen years ago,
a sudden wildfire broke out.
It burned the village to the ground.
No one survived.
The current residents
all moved there later on.
I remember Yunluo Village
sits right by the Tuoxi River.
Being that close to the water,
how could it have burned to the ground?
Find Xu Tong
and get me a map.
Yes, sir.
(Yunluo Village)
The terrain of Yunluo Village
slopes downward from west to east.
The Tuoxi River splits it
into a North and South village.
The mountains running east to west
block the winds
from the north and south.
The case files indicate
there was no wind that night.
The river was a firebreak.
So, what kind of inferno
(Tuoxi River, South and North Village)
could have reduced both villages
to nothing but ashes?
We asked the neighboring villages.
According to them,
that night,
no one heard a single cry
for help from Yunluo Village.
Naturally, no one cried out.
Because this
was no wildfire.
It was a deliberate act
to completely
destroy the evidence.
Tonight,
I expect to see
Di Renjie's corpse
hanging from the archway.
But...
He's an imperial official,
Madam!
So what?
What?
Is he untouchable?
Well...
I mean,
if you wanted to kill Xu Tong,
we'd do it without hesitation.
But Di Renjie
is an Imperial Commissioner!
You're a bandit.
You've lived comfortably for too long.
Have you forgotten what you are?
Who's there?
Beneath this bright moon,
gentlemen,
I'd like to recite another poem.
- Master.
- Wonderful.
Yunluo Village is gone.
Can we still find the temple
Madam Cui mentioned?
I went to Zhaoyun Temple
despite being heavily pregnant...
We can't overlook any clue.
Fog is rolling in.
Master, where did this fog come from?
Old blind man.
You heard everything?
Zhao De.
Stop this.
You
shouldn't have been born
with those ears!
The Colossus is here!
Run!
The Colossus is real.
Save him!
Go!
Move!
Master!
Di Renjie.
The matter of Yunluo Village
is not something you can investigate.
Di!
Master!
The arrow was poisoned.
I can't stop the bleeding.
I've used silver needles
to slow the blood flow
for now.
Aren't you a poison expert?
Cure him!
There is no antidote.
What do you mean?
You can't treat him?
Even you can't neutralize it?
Even a healer can't save him?
I could fight the poison with poison.
But the wound is too close to his heart.
A strong dose
could kill him instantly.
We have no choice.
We have to risk it.
No. Absolutely not.
If Commissioner Di dies,
I'll pay with my life.
What are you doing?
Testing the poison on myself.
Let me do it.
First, apply the poison to the wound.
Then, seal the Neiguan, Sanyinjiao,
and Taichong acupoints
with silver needles.
That will slow the bleeding.
Then, we test the antidotes.
Drink this.
No effect.
Still nothing.
Drink this.
Drink this one.
It's still bleeding.
It's not working.
The bleeding stopped.
It worked.
(Luling County Bureau)
Alright.
I'm here.
I'm here. Calm down.
That's enough. Settle down.
Where is Commissioner Di?
I need to see Commissioner Di.
If you have a grievance,
you can tell it to me.
I want to see Commissioner Di!
Well...
I am the magistrate of this county.
Whatever your grievance is,
you can tell me.
I want to see Commissioner Di!
He is not at the Bureau right now.
Hey, wait!
Listen.
Just tell me what the matter is.
I can handle your case just fine.
See that?
What's wrong with me?
At least give me a chance.
It's all my fault.
I failed to protect Master.
He will be alright.
- About earlier...
- Just now...
I was out of line. I apologize.
And thank you
for testing the poison for me.
It was nothing.
If you died,
who would save my master?
How do you and Commissioner Di
know each other?
A few years ago,
Master cleared my father's name
and got me out of Buliangjing.
He hired instructors
to teach me martial arts,
and raised me to be who I am now.
Buliangjing?
If you can't even read,
how did you learn to draw?
When my father died from false charges,
my mother and I
were banished to Buliangjing.
She was a woman of noble birth,
but just to fight for a scrap of food,
she was beaten to death.
I was only five.
After that,
I would take a wooden stick
and trace out her face in the dirt,
stroke by stroke.
Mother,
I miss you.
Over time,
I just got good at it.
Those drawings
must have been beautiful.
Di Renjie,
this case
is beyond your reach.
(Preview of Next Episode)
Today,
we are finally avenged.
Help me one last time.
- Mother!
- Madam!
This case
is beyond your reach.
♪Night covers the long streets♪
♪The city remains silent♪
♪Wind turns the old pages♪
♪Words still left unspoken♪
♪Bloodstains still hold their warmth♪
♪Lamplight slowly tilts aside♪
♪Who hides in the shadows♪
♪Still circling around the truth?♪
♪Love is born from desire♪
♪Hatred rises out of greed♪
♪One thought becomes a snare♪
♪A lifetime trapped within♪
♪Someone once warned me♪
♪To stop upon this shore♪
♪But sunlight burns too fiercely♪
♪Fragile eyes break too easily♪
♪If one thought retreats♪
♪Then all things rest in peace♪
♪But in this world♪
♪Who will make the final judgment?♪
♪If truth is cold as a frosted blade♪
♪Still I walk ahead♪
♪Let it pierce through♪
♪The illusions before my eyes♪
♪Layer upon layer of deception♪
♪Covering every heart♪
♪How many people♪
♪Weave their own cocoon♪
♪Yet call it♪
♪Fate?♪
♪Life and death♪
♪Balanced on a single line♪
♪Light and shadow♪
♪Hanging side by side♪
♪Goodness is not absolute♪
♪Nor is evil ever complete♪
♪In the end, it is only♪
♪A single misguided thought♪
♪If unveiling the truth♪
♪Requires abandoning tenderness♪
♪Then this answer♪
♪Can it still remain true?♪
♪When love and law♪
♪Stand against each other in silence♪
♪Which figure before me♪
♪Am I meant to believe?♪
♪If truth is cold as a frosted blade♪
♪Still I walk ahead♪
♪Not for fame or glory♪
♪Nor caring who wins or loses♪
♪Human nature is clouded♪
♪Yet still reflects the stars♪
♪Though this world♪
♪Is filled with mud and mire♪
♪There is still a light♪
♪Worth pursuing♪
♪Every case has its ending♪
♪But night does not always fade♪
♪The wind stops, the pages close♪
♪Yet hearts remain unsettled♪
♪If justice stands♪
♪Without mercy beside it♪
♪Then how is it♪
♪Any different from a blade?♪
♪If truth is cold as a frosted blade♪
♪Still I walk ahead♪
♪Even if the world♪
♪Refuses to answer♪
♪When every hidden truth♪
♪Finally reveals itself♪
♪I only wish♪
♪To hold on♪
♪Within the darkness♪
♪To the heart♪